Whitney T. Harden | Web Developer

Summary of Qualifications

Whitney is a front end developer who has worked on various websites as a freelancer and professionally as a developer for two organizations. In those roles she has guided clients on making development and design decisions with consideration to UX principles and accessibility. She is currently enrolled in Eleven Fifty Academy to further increase her knowledge in Web Development. Her experience includes building features, fixing bugs, and building web applications and platforms for various clients. Her strongest skills are HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. She also has experience with React.js, Node.js, and UX/UI Design. She is a problem-solver and loves to learn and be challenged.

Front End Development:

Enjoys working with teams and individually building great interfaces using front end technologies.

Technical Problem-solver:

Detail-oriented person who goes beyond the quick and easy answer to find the best solution.

Communication and Teamwork:

Effectively communicates via chat, e-mail, face-to-face, and video-conferencing tools such as Microsoft Teams, WebEx, Slack, and other similar software.

Flexibility and Adaptability:

Accustomed to working in a constantly changing work environment where I have been successful at adapting and working under pressure.

Skills

HTMLResponsive WebFigma

o CSS Development

JavaScriptAdobe CCSCSS/SassBootstrap

Experience

UX Consultant / Front End Developer

April 2019 – June 2020

Fusion Alliance Carmel, IN

Type of Work: Built Web Platforms, Web Pages, and features for clients;

Provide maintenance and updates for client websites.

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES5 and ES6),

Wordpress, Drupal, PHP, HubSpot, Git, Github, Bitbucket, Pantheon, JavaScript build tools, Lando, Command Line

Web Developer

January 2019 - March 2019

Finance of America Carmel, IN

Type of Work: Built Web Pages and features for various websites for the

company; Provides maintenance and updates for various

company websites.

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES5 and ES6),

Wordpress, PHP, Git, Pantheon, JavaScript build tools, Lando

Student Success Advisor

September 2011 – January 2019

Ivy Tech Community College

Indianapolis, IN

Type of Work: Assisted students with class enrollment, study skills, Present

study skills workshops; Assisted with Early Interventions

Strategies.

Tools Used: Banner, Microsoft Office

Volunteer Experience

Fusion Allies 2019 - 2020

Fusion Alliance

o Participated in Leadership and general meetings.

• Led or facilitated some meeting presentations, activities, and discussions.

Indy Women in Tech

2018 – Ongoing

Ivy Tech Community College

- Presented educational workshops with the goal of providing industry knowledge
- Served as panelist twice for two different panel discussions

Education

Web Development (Graduation: 01/2021)

Eleven Fifty Academy Fishers, IN

UX/UI Design

Eleven Fifty Academy Fishers, IN

Bachelor of Science in Athletic Training

Manchester University North Manchester, IN